Roma have also been discriminated against in Sweden.
During the 1900s, Roma were described as an inferior breed, based on racial biological ideas.
Many Roma were forcibly sterilized and children were taken from their parents.
Roma were not allowed to obtain housing and many were forced to live in camps.
It meant that Roma children could not go to school,
And adult Roma had a hard time getting a job.
Between 1914 and 1954, Roma was not allowed to travel to Sweden.
The Roma who already lived here could not leave the country because they were not allowed to come back.
On April 8, 1971, the first international Roma Congress was held in London.
Then they agreed on a Roman flag and a national anthem.
Since then, April 8 has been International Roma Day.
Racism against Roma Antiziganism-and political decisions during the 20th century have influenced the opportunities of the Romans to be part of Swedish society.
Roma still find it difficult to get housing and work.
Roma children face discrimination and difficulties in school.
But.
Roma should be able to participate in society on equal terms as others.
That is why in Sweden we have a national strategy for Roman inclusion.
The goal is for the Rome that turns 20 in 2032 to have the same opportunities in life as everyone else.